Partial Inventory of the Craig W. H. Luther papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Craig W. H. Luther papers
1937-2015
88064
Hoover Institution Archives
53 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box (23.3 linear feet)
Memoirs, diaries, questionnaire responses and interview summaries of military veterans, notes, photocopies of military records, printed matter, and photographs relating to German military operations during World War II, mainly on the Eastern Front. Used as research material for the books by Craig W. H. Luther, Blood and Honor: The History of the 12th SS Panzer Division "Hitler Youth, " 1943-1945 (San Jose, 1988), and Barbarossa Unleashed: The German Blitzkrieg through Central Russia to the Gates of Moscow, June-December 1941 (Atglen, Pa., 2013).
Luther, Craig W. H.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1988, with increments received in 2014, 2015, and 2017.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
American historian.
Scope and Content of Collection
The Craig W. H. Luther papers include questionnaire responses and letters by veterans of the German 12th SS-Panzerdivision "Hitlerjugend" and by veterans of Canadian, British, and Polish military units who fought against the 12th SS-Panzerdivision, as well as summaries of interviews with these veterans. These materials relate to activities of the 12th SS-Panzerdivision in World War II, and especially during the 1944 Normandy campaign. Used as research material for Luther's book, Blood and Honor: The History of the 12th SS Panzer Division "Hitler Youth," 1943-1945 (San Jose, 1988).
An increment received in 2015 consists of research materials, soldier questionnaires, memoirs, and other materials relating to Luther's Strategic Withdrawal of German Army Groups South and Center to the Dnepr River and First Soviet Attempts to Capture Kiev, August-October 1943, as well as Barbarossa Unleashed: The German Blitzkrieg through Central Russia to the Gates of Moscow, June-December 1941.
Waffen-SS. SS-Panzerdivision "Hitlerjugend," 12.; Nationalsozialistische Deutsche Arbeiter-Partei.; National socialism.; World War, 1939-1945--Campaigns--France--Normandy.; World War, 1939-1945--Campaigns--Eastern Front.
- Interviews with veterans, 1981-1983 (Box 1)
- 2014 Incremental Materials (Boxes 2-4)
  Scope and Contents note
  Not yet described.
- 2015 Incremental Materials, 1992-2014 (Boxes 5-41)
  Research materials, soldier questionnaires, memoirs, and materials relating to Craig Luther's Strategic Withdrawal of German Army Groups South and Center to the Dnepr River and First Soviet Attempts to Capture Kiev, August-October 1943, as well as Barbarossa Unleashed: The German Blitzkrieg through Central Russia to the Gates of Moscow, June-December 1941.
  - Kiev 1943 Project, 2000-2014
    Materials referenced in Luther's Strategic Withdrawal of German Army Groups South and Center to the Dnepr River and First Soviet Attempts to Capture Kiev, August-October 1943.
    - Art of War Symposium, 2000 (Box-folder 5: 1)
    - Correspondence, 2013-2014 (Box-folder 5: 2)
    - "Battle for the Dnepr, September-October 1943" by D. Glantz, 2000s (Box-folder 5: 3)
    - Captured German records from the National Archives, 2000s (Box-folder 5: 4)
    - Das Deutsche Heer, 1939-1945 by Wolf Keilig and Burkhart Müeller-Hillebrand, 2000s (Box-folder 5: 5)
    - Doctrine / tactics, 2000s (Box-folder 5: 6)
      Includes Standing Fast: German Defensive Doctrine on the Russian Front During World War II by Major Timothy A. Wray and The Anvil of War by Generaloberst Erhard Rauss and Generalluetnant Oldwig Von Natzmer.
    - Dramatis Personae, 2000s (Box-folder 5: 7)
      Includes Generalfeldmarschall Walter Model: Legende und Wirklichkeit. Materials in German.
    - DZRW / Bd. 5/2, 2000s (Box-folder 5: 8)
      Includes Das Deutsche Reich und Der Zweite Weltkrieg by Zweiter Halbband.
    - Foreign military studies, 2000s (Box-folder 5: 9)
    - German Army miscellaneous data, 2000s (Box-folder 6: 1)
    - German Army order of battles / Stellenbesetzungen, 2000s (Box-folder 6: 2)
    - Heeresgruppen Süd, 2000s (Box-folder 6: 3)
    - Adolf Hitler, 2000s (Box-folder 6: 4)
    - Kriegstagebuch des Oberkommandos der Wehrmacht, 2000s (Box-folder 6: 5)
    - Die Geheimen Tagesberichte der Deutschen Wehrmachtführung im Zweiten Weltkrieg, 2000s (Box-folder 6: 6)
    - Lagekarten, 2000s (Box-folder 6: 7)
    - "The Phantom Barrier: Ostwallbau 1944-1945,", 2000s (Box-folder 6: 8)
    - Scorched Earth, 2000s (Box-folder 6: 9)
      Includes Deutsche Soldaten - nationalsozialistischer Krieg.
    - "Strategic Thinking of Adolf Hitler and the German High Command,", 2000s (Box-folder 6: 10)
    - Battle for the Dnepr River, chapter one notes and outline, 2000s (Box-folder 6: 11)
    - The Battle for the Dnepr River: The Soviet Advance on the Kiev Axis by David M. Glantz and Craig Luther, 2000s (Box-folder 6: 12)
    - Das Deutsche Reich und der Zweite Weltkrieg, 2007 (Box-folder 6: 13)
  - War diaries and memoirs, 1992-2007
    Photocopies of German war diaries.
    - Copies of war diaries, 2000s (Box-folder 7: 1)
    - T-354: SS Flak Abt. "Das Reich." Gefechtsberichte u. Erfolgs-meldungen (Nr. 78008/17 / Roll 125), 2000s (Box-folder 7: 2)
    - "Ia, Anlagenband 5 zum Kriegstagebuch 2. Gefechts- u. Verpflegungsstaerken (1.1.-21.9.43) (Roll 724),", 2000s (Box-folder 7: 3)
    - T-314: Anlagenband I 1, Ia Kriegstagebuch 56 Panzerkorps (Sep-Oct 43) (Nr. 49847/1 / Roll 1431), 2000s (Box-folder 7: 4)
    - T-314: Ia Kriegstagebuch Gen. Kdo. 48 Panzerkorps (Sep 43) (Nr. 49011/3 / Roll 1170), 2000s (Box-folder 7: 5)
    - T-314: Abt. Qu. Anlagen zum Kriegstagebuch Nr. 1 u. 2, Gen.Kdo. 48 Panzerkorps (1.9.-31.10.43) (Nr. 40773/41 / Roll 1170), 2000s (Box-folder 7: 6)
    - T-314: Ia Kriegstagebuch 3/43, Gen. Kdo. 24 Panzerkorps (24.9.-31.12.43) (Nr. 50465/3 / Roll 727), 2000s (Box-folder 7: 7)
    - T-314: Ia Kriegstagebuch 2/43, Gen. Kdo. 24 Panzerkorps (16.8.-23.9.43) (Nr. 50465/2 / Roll 727), 2000s (Box-folder 7: 8)
    - T-314: Ia Kriegstagebuch Nr. 6, Gen. Kdo. 59 AK (10.9-2.11.43) (Nr. 49914/1 / Roll 1517), 2000s (Box-folder 7: 9)
    - T-314 13 AK: Ia Anlagen zum Kriegstagebuch, Kriegsgliederungen (1.8.-1.12.43) (Nr. 42305/3 / Roll 521), 2000s (Box-folder 7: 10)
    - 13 AK: Ia Kriegstagebuch Nr. 12 (24.8.-31.12.43) (Nr. 45449/1 / Roll 521), 2000s (Box-folder 7: 11)
    - Heeresgruppe Mitte, Abt. Ia, Anlagen zum Kriegstagebuch (Nr. 65002 / Roll 221), 2000s (Box-folder 7: 12)
    - T-312: AOK 2 Kriegstagebuch Russland, Teil 13 (26.8.-30.9.43) (Nr. 48318 / Roll 1272), 2000s (Box-folder 7: 13)
    - "T-312 AOK 8: Kriegstagebuch Nr. 2, Ia Kriegsgliederungen (Jul - Dec 43) (Nr. 44701 / Roll 55),", 2000s (Box-folder 7: 14)
    - "T-313: Panzer. AOK 4 Kriegstagebuch, Bd. 1 (1.8.-30.9.43) (Nr. 41631 / Roll 372),", 2000s (Box-folder 7: 15)
    - N 507: Handakten GFM v. Mansteins als Oberbefehlshaber der Heeresgruppe süd, 2000s (Box-folder 8: 1-2)
    - RH 2/3061 and 3062: Kriegstagebuch der Op. Abt. des Generalstabes im OKH, 2000s (Box-folder 8: 3-4)
    - Kriegstagebuch Karte Panzer. AOK 4, 2000s (Box-folder 8: 5)
    - Panzer. AOK 4 / Fiendlagekarten, 2000s (Box-folder 8: 6)
    - AOK 8 records, 2000s (Box-folder 8: 7)
    - AOK 8 Karten (15-30/9/1943), 2000s (Box-folder 8: 8)
    - AOK 8 / Daily Operations Maps (1-31/10/1943), 2000s (Box-folder 9: 1)
    - Red Army 1943, 2000s (Box-folder 9: 2)
    - Soviet summer offensives (general), 2000s (Box-folder 9: 3-4)
      Includes The Russo-German War, July 1943-May 1945, Defense Against Russian Breakthroughs edited by W. Victor Madej, When the Titans Clashed: How the Red Army Stopped Hitler, The Battle of Kursk by David M. Glantz, and various articles.
    - Units: Infantry division, 2000s (Box-folder 9: 4-5)
    - Units: Panzer division, 2000s (Box-folder 9: 6-7)
    - "Fire Brigades: The Panzer Divisions" by Kamen Nevenkin, 2000s (Box-folder 9: 8)
    - Generalfeldmarschall Erich Von Manstein, 2000s (Box-folder 10: 1-2)
    - Memoirs, 2000s (Box-folder 10: 3-4)
    - "Weißt du noch, Kamerad? Die Geschichte einer Infanterie-Kompanie im Osten,", 2000s (Box-folder 10: 5)
    - Barkhoff, Günter (infanterie-regiment 77 / 26. infanterie-division), 2000s (Box-folder 10: 6)
    - Becker, Klaus (Flak /Heeresgruppe Mitte), 2000s (Box-folder 10: 7)
    - Dill, Hans J. (10. / SR 304 / 2. panzerdivision), 2000s (Box-folder 10: 8)
    - Hertenstein, Rolf, "The Experience of a World War II German Panzer Commander,", 1992 (Box-folder 11: 1)
    - Groth (Feldwebel) (infanterie-regiment 256 / 112. infanterie-division), 2000s (Box-folder 11: 2)
    - Hermann, Alfred (Nahaufklärungsstaffel), 2006 (Box-folder 11: 3)
    - Hoffmann, Alfred (Unteroffizier) (197. infanterie-division), 2001 (Box-folder 11: 4)
    - Krehl, Eberhard (Unteroffizier Stabsfeldwebel), 2007 (Box-folder 11: 5)
    - Kreuter, Georg Christian (SR 101 / 18. panzerdivision), 2007 (Box-folder 11: 6)
    - Kummer, Kurt (4. / artillerieregiment 88 (mot) / 18. panzerdivision), 2004 (Box-folder 11: 7)
    - Loewer, Willi (artillerieregiment 129 / 129. infanterie-division), 2000s (Box-folder 11: 8)
    - Loheide, Hermann (infanterie-regiment 278 / 95. infanterie-division), 2000s (Box-folder 11: 9)
    - Moeller, Johannes (Memoiren / 86. infanterie-division), 2005 (Box-folder 11: 10)
    - Neuser, Walter (artillerieregiment 59 / 23. infanterie-division), 2003 (Box-folder 11: 11-12)
    - Hans-Otto, 2007 (Box-folder 12: 1)
    - Richter, Georg (artillerieregiment 74 / 2. panzerdivision), 2000s (Box-folder 12: 2)
    - Rupp-Tagebuch (transcription), 2005 (Box-folder 12: 3)
    - Rupp, Robert (17 panzerdivision / IFZ), 2003 (Box-folder 12: 4)
    - Sartoro, Heinz, 2003 (Box-folder 12: 5)
    - Schaefer-Kehnert, Walter (Panzer. artillerieregiment 119 / 11. Panzerdivision), 2000s (Box-folder 12: 6)
    - Scheuer, Alois (197. infanterie-division), 2000s (Box-folder 12: 7)
    - Schickner, Wilhelm (2. panzerdivision), 2000s (Box-folder 12: 8)
    - Hauptfeldwebel Weller (infanterie-regiment 480 / 260 infanterie-division), 2007 (Box-folder 12: 9)
    - Wurster, Gottlieb (35 infanterie-division), 2006 (Box-folder 12: 10)
    - BfZ / Stuttgart Feldpostbriefe, 2004 (Box-folder 12: 11)
    - Heinemann, Werner (infanterie-regiment 67 / 23. infanterie-division), 2000s (Box-folder 13: 1-2)
  - Interviews and questionnaires with German soldiers from the Eastern Front, 2002-2009
    Interviews, questionnaires, and correspondence with German soldiers from the Eastern Front (labeled "ostfront kämpfer"), arranged alphabetically.
    - Adler, Rudolf - Andres, Kurt Werner, 2004-2006 (Box-folder 13: 3)
    - Bäse, Otto - Beyrich, Martin, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 13: 4)
    - Bock, Günter - Bremer, Walter, 2006-2007 (Box-folder 13: 5)
    - Bruenger, Helmet - Bunke, Erich, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 13: 6)
    - Dicke, Werner - Drews, Martin, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 13: 7)
    - Effing, Heinz - Gutenkunst, Alfred, 2002-2005 (Box-folder 14: 1)
    - Hahn, Johannes - Krombholz, Erwin, 2005 (Box-folder 14: 2)
    - Krueger, Arthur - Loewer, Willi, 2005-2006 (Box-folder 14: 3)
    - Mayer, Hein - Regeniter, Alfred, 2002-2004 (Box-folder 14: 4)
    - Schaefer-Kehnert, Walter - Schillke, Hans, 2003-2005 (Box-folder 14: 5)
    - Schmidt, Albert - Soff, Heinz, 2003-2005 (Box-folder 14: 6)
    - Sohn, Hermann - Stoves, Rolf O. G., 2004 (Box-folder 14: 7)
    - Strienitz, Fritz - Stühlmeyer, Heinrich, 2007 (Box-folder 14: 8)
    - Trotsch, Otto - Vierkorn, Karl-Gottfried, 2004-2009 (Box-folder 15: 1)
    - Vollmer, Walter - Vornholt, Erich, 2004-2009 (Box-folder 15: 2)
    - Wagemann, Eberhard - Wardin, Eberhard, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 15: 3)
    - Wardin, Eberhard, 2000s (Box-folder 15: 4-6)
    - Weingarten, Emmerich - Wexel, Heinz, 2007 (Box-folder 15: 7)
    - Will, Otto, 2005 (Box-folder 15: 8)
    - Willich, Eberhard - Zirk, George, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 15: 9)
  - Barbarossa Unleashed Project, 1993-2014
    Research materials related to Barbarossa Unleashed: The German Blitzkrieg through Central Russia to the Gates of Moscow, June-December 1941.
    - Barbarossa Projeckt '41/42 (veterans' correspondence), undated (Box-folder 16: 1-4)
    - Operation Typhoon maps, 2000s (Box-folder 16: 5)
    - CD-R labeled "Defeat of German Forces at Moscow,", 2000s (Box-folder 16: 6)
    - "Defeat of German Forces at Moscow," Soviet General Staff study completed in 1943, Volume 1, 2000s (Box-folder 16: 7-10)
      Materials in Russian.
    - "Defeat of German Forces at Moscow," Soviet General Staff study completed in 1943, Volume 3, 2000s (Box-folder 17: 1-2)
    - Copy of Великая отечественная, 2006 (Box-folder 17: 2-3)
    - Photos and photocopies of photos taken by German troops in Russia in 1941, 2011 (Box-folder 17: 4-6, Box-folder 18: 1-2)
      Photos used in Barbarossa Unleashed.
    - Photo essay 1 for Barbarossa Unleashed, 2000s (Box-folder 18: 3)
    - Photo essay 2 for Barbarossa Unleashed, 2000s (Box-folder 18: 4)
    - Photo essay 3 for Barbarossa Unleashed, 2000s (Box-folder 18: 5)
    - Photos with USB drive and CD-R, 2012 (Box-folder 18: 6)
    - Photos, 1999 (Box-folder 18: 6)
    - Photos, 2000s (Box-folder 19: 1-2)
    - Photos, 2012 (Box-folder 19: 3)
    - Photos, 2011 (Box-folder 19: 4)
    - Photos, 2012 (Box-folder 19: 5)
    - Complete set of maps and photos used for Barbarossa Unleashed on USB drive, 2000s (Box-folder 19: 6)
    - Six CDs containing electronic files, 1 unlabeled USB drive, 2013 (Box-folder 19: 7)
    - Photos and correspondence, 2014 (Box-folder 19: 8)
    - Six CDs containing photographs, 2000s (Box-folder 19: 9)
    - Photos and correspondence, 2000s (Box-folder 19: 10)
    - Six reels of microfilm from the National Archives, 2000s (Box-folder 20: 1)
    - Four unclassified microfilm reels, 2000s (Box-folder 20: 2)
    - "Ostfeldzug 1943 Withdrawal of German Army Groups South and Center to the Dnepr River and First Soviet Attempts to Capture Kiev, Volumes 1-4," research notes prepared by Craig Luther, 2013 (Box-folder 21: 1-4)
    - Wofür? Erlebnisberichte deutscher Soldaten im Rußlandkrieg 1941-1946, 1993 (Box-folder 21: 5)
    - Gesallen! Und umsonst. Erlebnisberichte deutscher Soldaten im Rußlandkrieg 1941-1946, 1993-2008 (Box-folder 21: 6)
    - From the Other Side: A Collection of Personal WWII Stories by Horst Pagel, undated (Box-folder 22: 1)
    - "Ostfront 1941-1945: Ein Soldatenleben. Aufgezeichnet von Günter Barkhoff Essen,", undated (Box-folder 22: 2)
  - Oversized materials, undated
    - Several maps for Kiev 1943 Project, 1 photo album, and several maps for Barbarossa Unleashed, undated (Box 23)
  - Photocopies of materials regarding German military units, 2002-2008
    Materials primarily in German.
    - 1. Kavallerie-Division, 2000s (Box-folder 24: 1-2)
    - 3. Infanterie-Division, 2000s (Box-folder 24: 3)
    - 6. Infanterie-Division, Heinrich Stockhoff, 2000s (Box-folder 24: 4-5)
    - 6. Infanterie-Division - 10. Infanterie Division, 2000s (Box-folder 24: 6-11)
    - 11. Infanterie-Division, 2000s (Box-folder 25: 1)
    - 14. Infanterie-Division Mot. (motorized infantry division), 2000s (Box-folder 25: 2-5)
    - 14. Infanterie-Division Mot. (motorized infantry division), Kriegstagebuch, 2000s (Box-folder 25: 6-7)
    - Heeresgruppe Mitte Kriegstagebuch, October 1941, 2000s (Box-folder 25: 8-9)
    - Heeresgruppe Mitte Kriegstagebuch, November 1941, 2000s (Box-folder 26: 1)
    - Heeresgruppe Mitte Kriegstagebuch, December 1941, 2000s (Box-folder 26: 2)
    - Heeresgruppe Mitte Kriegstagebuch Anlagebande, 2000s (Box-folder 26: 3)
    - Das Pionier-Bataillon 6 im Feldzug gegen Russland, 2000s (Box-folder 26: 4-7)
    - 17. Infanterie-Division - 26. Infanterie-Division, 2000s (Box-folder 26: 8-10)
    - 29. Infanterie-Division - 78. Infanterie-Division, 2000s (Box-folder 27: 1-11)
    - 86. Infanterie-Division - 197. Infanterie-Division, 2000s (Box-folder 28: 1-11)
    - 251. Infanterie-Division - 292. Infanterie-Division, 2000s (Box-folder 29: 1-10)
      Includes one CD-R (in folder 3).
    - 292. Infanterie-Division - 330. Infanterie-Division, 2000s (Box-folder 30: 1-6)
    - "Grossdeutschland Infanterie-Division,", 2000s (Box-folder 30: 7)
    - Infanterie-Regiment Grossdeutschland, 2000s (Box-folder 30: 8)
    - Schutzstaffel Kavallerie Brigade, 2000s (Box-folder 30: 9)
    - Schutzstaffel Regiment "Deutschland,", 2000s (Box-folder 30: 10-11)
    - Schutzstaffel Panzergrenadier Regiments 4, 2000s (Box-folder 31: 1)
    - Schutzstaffel Infanterie Regiments "Langemarck,", 2000s (Box-folder 31: 2)
    - 1. Panzerdivision - 3. Panzerdivision, 2000s (Box-folder 31: 3-8)
    - 4. Panzerdivision - 11. Panzerdivision, 2000s (Box-folder 32: 1-8)
    - 11. Panzerdivision - 20. Panzerdivision, 2000s (Box-folder 33: 1-8)
    - Sturmgeschütz-Abteilung / Brigade 210, 2003 (Box-folder 33: 9)
    - Sturmgeschütz Brigade 660 and 259, 2000s (Box-folder 33: 10)
    - Foreign Legions (Freiwillige), 2000s (Box-folder 34: 1)
    - 2nd Schutzstaffel Panzer Division Das Reich, 2002-2004 (Box-folder 34: 2-4)
    - IX Armeekorps, 2000s (Box-folder 34: 5)
    - XXIII Armeekorps Kriegstagebuch, 2000s (Box-folder 34: 6)
    - LIII Armeekorps 2. Panzerarmee "Verteidigung an der OKA,", 2002 (Box-folder 34: 7)
    - 2. Panzer Armeeoberkommandos Kriegstagebuch, 2000s (Box-folder 34: 8-9)
    - "Die Operationen der 2. Panzer Armee in der Doppelschlacht von Bryansk und Wyazma und beim Vorstoss auf Moskau,", 2008 (Box-folder 35: 1)
    - "Kriegstagebuch 22. 7. 1941,", 2000s (Box-folder 35: 2)
    - "Kriegstagebuch 8. 8. 1941,", 2000s (Box-folder 35: 3)
    - Armeeoberkommandos 4., 2000s (Box-folder 35: 4-5)
    - "Kriegstagebuch der Chef des Stabes,", 2000s (Box-folder 35: 6)
    - 4. Panzerkorps / 3. Panzergruppe, 2000s (Box-folder 35: 7-8)
    - Panzer Armeeoberkommandos 4. Kriegstagebuch, 2000s (Box-folder 36: 1-2)
    - Panzer Armeeoberkommandos 4. "Kaempfe vor Moskau,", 2000s (Box-folder 36: 3)
    - Kriegstagebuch Heeresgruppe Mitte "Anlagebaende, etc.,", 2003 (Box-folder 36: 4-6)
    - Kriegstagebuch June - July 1941, 2000s (Box-folder 36: 7-10)
    - Kriegstagebuch Anlagebaende, 2004 (Box-folder 37: 1-2)
    - Erinnerungen Nachlass von Weichs, 2000s (Box-folder 37: 3)
    - Generaloberst Hans Reinhardt, 2000s (Box-folder 37: 4)
    - Erich Miethe, 2000s (Box-folder 37: 5)
    - General Lemelsen (tagebuch), 2005-2006 (Box-folder 37: 6-7)
    - Nachlass Kaumann, 2005-2006 (Box-folder 37: 8)
    - Nachlass Hoepner, 2000s (Box-folder 37: 9)
    - Karlsruhe Collection (Luftwaffe), 2000s (Box-folder 38: 1-4)
    - Flakartillerie, 2000s (Box-folder 38: 5)
    - "Kriegsverbrechen der russischen Wehrmacht,", 2006 (Box-folder 38: 6-7)
    - 290. Infanterie-Division "Chronik in Bildern,", 2000s (Box-folder 38: 8)
    - 290. Infanterie-Division, 2000s (Box-folder 39: 1)
    - 292. Infanterie-Division, 2000s (Box-folder 39: 2)
    - Photocopy of Wolchow: 900 Tage Kampf um Leningrad by Hartwig Pohlman, 2000s (Box-folder 39: 3)
    - "General der Panzertruppe a.D. Walter K. Nehring" by Günter A. Schultze, 2000s (Box-folder 39: 4)
    - Aufzeichnungen aus der Sturzkampffliegerei by Von Major a. D. Friedrich Lang, 2000s (Box-folder 39: 5)
    - "Winter-Schlacht" and "Rübckblick und Bilanz" by Eberhard Wardin, 2000s (Box-folder 39: 6-7)
  - Photocopies of unclassified military reports from the National Archives and Records Administration, 2000s
    Materials in English and German.
    - "The Fighting Qualities of the Russian Soldiers" by Dr. Erich Rendulic, 2000s (Box-folder 39: 8)
    - "War Experiences in Russia" by Lieutenant General von Unruh, 2000s (Box-folder 39: 9)
    - "Rocket Projectors in the Eastern Theater" by Graewe, 2000s (Box-folder 39: 10)
    - "Winter Fighting of the 253rd Infantry Division in the Rzhev Area in 1941-1942" by Otto Schellert, 2000s (Box-folder 39: 11)
    - "Horse Diseases during the Eastern Campaign" by Dr. Maximilian Betzler, 2000s (Box-folder 39: 12)
    - "Protection of the Lines of Communication in the East" by Gustav von Bechtolsheim, 2000s (Box-folder 39: 13)
    - "Second Army Gets Out of the Mud" by General Gustav Harteneck, 2000s (Box-folder 39: 14)
    - "The Winter Battle of Rzhev, Vyazma, and Yuknov, 1941-1942" by Oberst Otto Dessloch, 2000s (Box-folder 39: 15)
    - "Campaign of the 255th Infantry Division East and South of Temkino" by Walter F. Poppe, 2000s (Box-folder 39: 16)
    - "The Capture of Smolensk by the 71st Motorized Infantry Regiment on 15 July 1941" by Thomas, 2000s (Box-folder 40: 1)
    - "An Artillery Regiment on the Road to Moscow" by General Major Gerhard Grassman, 2000s (Box-folder 40: 2)
    - "Supply by Air" Dietrich Lemcke, 2000s (Box-folder 40: 3)
    - "Advance and Battles of the 11th Infantry Division" by Heinz Gaede, 2000s (Box-folder 40: 4)
    - "German Preparations for the Attack Against Russia" by Cuno, 2000s (Box-folder 40: 5)
    - "Antitank Defense in the East" by Erich Schneider, 2000s (Box-folder 40: 6)
    - "488th Infantry Regiment Attack on Vyazma" by Wilhelm Koehler, 2000s (Box-folder 40: 7)
    - "The 35th Infantry Division Between Moscow and Gzhatsk" by Rudolf von Roman, 2000s (Box-folder 40: 8)
    - "The 547th Infantry Regiment Advance and Fighting under Winter Conditions" by Karl Becher, 2000s (Box-folder 40: 9)
    - "March and Traffic Control of Panzer Divisions with Special Attention to Conditions in the Soviet Union and in Africa" and "German Tank Strength and Loss Statistics" by Burkhart Mueller-Hillebrand, 2000s (Box-folder 40: 10)
    - "Tank Repair Service in the German Army" and "Organization of the Army High Command" by Burkhart Mueller-Hillebrand, 2000s (Box-folder 40: 11)
    - "Combat in Forests and Swamps" by Hans von Greiffenberg, 2000s (Box-folder 40: 12)
    - "Battle of Moscow" by Hans von Greiffenberg, 2000s (Box-folder 40: 13-14)
    - "Battle of Moscow" by Hans von Greiffenberg, 2000s (Box-folder 41: 1)
    - "Transportation of Replacements by Post Office Busses to the Eastern From in Winter 1942/1942" by Hermann Hans Guenther Keil, 2000s (Box-folder 41: 2)
    - "Personal Diary Notes of the G-4 of the German 9th Army" by Generalmajor Windisch, 2000s (Box-folder 41: 3-5)
    - "Eastern Campaign" by Generalleutnant Adolf Heusinger, 2000s (Box-folder 41: 6)
    - "Terrain Factors in the Russian Campaign" by General der Infanterie Karl Allmendinger, 2000s (Box-folder 41: 7)
    - "Conversations with a Stuka Pilot" conference materials, 2000s (Box-folder 41: 8)
  - Correspondence, 2003
    - One letter from Karl Gottfried Vierkorn to Craig Luther, 2003 (Box-folder 41: 9)
- 2017 Incremental Materials (Boxes 42-54)